# **Paula Arenas**

**Email**: Paula@Arenas.se, **Address**: 117 New Road, Woodston, Peterborough **Phone**: 07778 446570

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Senior System Developer with a Master of Science in computer science and with over 10 years of work experience in .NET based development, databases, web development and design.

Experienced full-stack developer with great understanding of all kinds of web projects and with a specialist competence in development based on EPiServer Content Management System.

Certified Scrum Master with long experience of working in agile projects, and also experienced in taking the role as a Technical Lead, Application manager or Technical Project Manager.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

### **System Development**

C#, ASP.NET, MVC, Webforms, XML, MS-SQL, LINQ, Entity Framework.

#### Web development

EPiServer, HTML, CSS, AJAX, Javascript, JQuery, ReactJS, Webservices, XSLT, JSON.

#### Tools

Microsoft Visual Studio, Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio, IIS, TFS, GitHub, SoapUI, Visual Source Safe.

## **Methods**

**SCRUM** 

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

# **Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)**

2016

Levla AB, Stockholm

## **LANGUAGES**

Swedish: Native English: Fluent

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Senior System Developer & Tech Lead SEAVUS (consultancy firm) Stockholm, Sweden	2016 - 2019
Senior System Developer & Tech Lead OTTOBONI (web agency) Stockholm, Sweden	2015
Senior System Developer & Tech Lead HIQ (consultancy firm) Stockholm, Sweden	2013 - 2015
System Developer SALUSANSVAR (insurance company) Stockholm, Sweden	2012 - 2013
System Developer TIETO (consultancy firm) Stockholm, Sweden	2011 - 2012
System Engineer BNEARIT(consultancy firm) Luleå, Sweden	2008 - 2011
.NET Developer OFFICE I NORRBOTTEN (IT service provider) Luleå, Sweden	2008

# **EDUCATION**

MSc programme in Computer Science and Engineering	2002 - 2007
Luleå University of Technology, Luleå, Sweden	
Department of Computer Science and Electrical Engineering	
Divison of Computer Communication	

MASTER'S THESIS: "REDS - Redundant and Expandable Distributed file Storage system for a serverless network".

Supervisor: Professor Douglas C. Sicker, Department of Computer Science, University of Colorado at Boulder, USA

Preparatory Programme in Technology Luleå University of Technology, Luleå, Sweden Department of Computer Science and Electrical Engineering	2001 – 2002
<b>The Social Science Programme – Economics</b> Hermelinsskolan, Luleå, Sweden	1998 - 2001
<b>Elementary School</b> Bergviksskolan, Luleå, Sweden	1989 - 1998

#### **EXAMPLE OF COMPLETED PROJECTS**

## **TIETO, Stockholm**

2018 - 2019

Application Manager / Technical Lead

Application Manager and Technical Lead, responsible for transitioning a large healthcare system from an old supplier. This web based prescribing system is used for handling medical aid for people with disabilities. The role as Application Manager / Technical Lead involved managing and also be a part of the development team, as well as having a close communication with the client to meet their requirements.

**Tools & Technologies:** C#.NET, MVC, Webforms, EPiServer, WCF, SQL, Javascript, XSLT, Visual Studio, Git, SoapUI

#### FOLKSAM, Stockholm

2017

Technical Lead / Senior EPiServer Developer

Development of websites for KPA Pension, the Swedish leading pension company in the local authority sector, who are entrusted with the pensions of over one million people. The work involved development of new sites with high focus on usability and availability for mobile devices. The role involved close communication with the client, as well as knowledge sharing with the rest of the development team.

**Tools & Technologies:** Web development, C#.NET, MVC, EPiServer CMS 9 , Visual Studio, Microsoft SQL Server, Team Foundation Server, JQuery, ReactJS, TypeScript, CSS3, HTML5, Scrum.

### **COMPREND, Stockholm**

2016

Senior System Developer

Development of multiple websites for SEB, a leading Nordic financial service group. This project involved both intranet sites and public sites for SEB, all based on EPiServer. The intranet sites had a new search platform that the websites had to be integrated to.

**Tools & Technologies**: Web development, C#.NET, MVC, EPiServer CMS 9, Visual Studio, Microsoft SQL Server, Team Foundation Server, Javascript, CSS, Scrum.

## **OTTOBONI, Stockholm**

2015

Technical Lead / Senior System Developer

- Development of an intranet for the Bambora Group, a Nordic-based payment service group, offering online, in-store and mobile payment solution services. The website is based on EPiServer and is running as a Windows Azure using Azure Active Directory for user authentication.
- Maintenance of websites based on EPiServer CMS 5, 6, 7 and 8.

The role involved managing and to be part of the development team, creating requirement specifications, close communication with the client.

**Tools & Technologies:** Web development and maintenance, C#.NET, MVC, EPiServer, Visual Studio, Microsoft SQL Server, Team Foundation Server, Javascript, CSS.

#### THE SWEDISH TAX AGENCY, Stockholm

2014 - 2015

Senior System Developer

Development of KPI reports for the Swedish tax agency. This Project involved work with requirement specification, analysis, development and design for the reports.

Tools & Technologies: System development, Crystal Report.

### MIDROC, Stockholm

2014

Senior System Developer

Development of a time reporting web portal to support the company's operations. The work involved web development and integration with the underlying systems.

**Tools & Technologies:** Web development, C#.NET, Visual Studio, Microsoft SQL Server, Team Foundation Server, WCF, Javascript, CSS.

#### **NONVIOLENCE FOUNDATION, Stockholm**

2013 - 2014

Technical Lead / Senior System Developer

Development of websites, based on EPiServer CMS, for The Non-Violence Project Foundation. The role as Technical Project Manager involved being responsible for the architectural questions, as well as close communication with the client. The role also involved supervising and managing a trainee for 6 month.

**Tools & Technologies**: Web development, C#.NET, MVC, EPiServer CMS 7, Visual Studio, Microsoft SQL Server, Team Foundation Server, Javascript, CSS, Scrum.

# SALUSANSVAR, Stockholm

2012 - 2013

System Developer

Development and maintenance of the website for SalusAnsvar, a Swedish insurance company. The website is based on EPiServer CMS and has integrations to underlying insurance systems.

**Tools & Technologies**: Web development and maintenance, C#.NET, EPiServer CMS 6, Visual Studio, Microsoft SQL Server, Team Foundation Server, Javascript, CSS, Scrum.

# **LUDVIKA MUNICIPALITY, Stockholm**

2012

Technical Project Manager / System Developer

Development of e-services to enable online applications for childcare, construction permits and serving licenses. This solution is based on EPiServer CMS and contains integration to external systems. The role as a Technical Project manager involved an overall responsibility for the solution and also Managing the development team on a day to day basis.

**Tools & Technologies**: Web development, C#.NET, EPiServer CMS 6, Visual Studio, Microsoft SQL Server, Team Foundation Server, Javascript.

#### **ENTERCARD, Stockholm**

2010-2011

Technical Project Manager / System Developer

Development of a web-based installment solution where the application for credit is done online and in real-time. Both the end-user GUI and the administration website are based on EPiServer CMS.

**Tools & Technologies**: Web development, C#.NET, EPiServer CMS 6, Visual Studio, Microsoft SQL Server, Team Foundation Server, Javascript, CSS.

## **GLOBEFORUM, Stockholm**

2010

Technical Project Manager / System Developer

Development, technical project management, testing and documentation of the online community Globe Forum, built on EPiServer CMS. The Globe Forum online community aims to tackle issues of global sustainability and environmental degradation through crowdsourcing.

**Tools & Technologies**: Web development, C#.NET, EPiServer CMS 5, EPiServer Relate+, Visual Studio 2008, Microsoft SQL Server 2008, Team Foundation Server, Javascript, Scrum.

**GENISIS IT, Luleå** 

2010

System Developer

Development of a web portal for ByggTrygg, a service company for construction dealers in Sweden. The portal was developed using Coolite, a tool built on the ExtJS Javascript framework.

**Tools & Technologies**: Web development, Coolite, C#.NET, Visual Source Safe, Visual Studio 2008, Microsoft SQL Server 2008, AJAX.

### XL-BYGG STENVALLS, Luleå

2009

System Developer

Development of a web shop for construction dealers and entrepreneurs. The web shop is a tool to assemble and register work orders to the end-customers. The work involved web development, integration with underlying order management system, development and implementation of the graphical design. The work also included implementation of an administration interface to manage products and users of the web shop.

**Tools & Technologies**: Web development, graphical design, C#, ASP.NET 3.5, Visual Studio 2008, Visual Source Safe, Crystal Report, AJAX, CSS, Javascript, Webservices.

## **GENISIS IT, Luleå**

2009

System Developer

Development of an application to handle timber. The application is managing the entire process chain from a forest felling prospectus to final measurement. A graphical user interface was also developed for the application.

**Tools & Technologies:** System development, C#.NET, Visual Source Safe, Visual Studio 2008, Microsoft SQL Server 2008.

### **APOTEKET FARMACI, Stockholm**

2008 - 2009

System Developer

Development, test, design and documentation of website for the Swedish national pharmacy. The website is based on Windows SharePoint Services.

**Tools & Technologies**: Web development, C#.NET, Visual Studio 2008, Team Foundation Server, Microsoft SQL Server 2008, SharePoint, CSS, Javascript.

## **OFFICE IN NORRBOTTEN, Luleå**

2008

Design and web development of an intranet based on Windows SharePoint Services.

**Tools & Technologies**: Web development, ASP.NET 3.5, C#, SharePoint Designer, Visual studio 2008, Team Foundation Server.

# **DATAMETRIX, Luleå**

2008

System Developer

Design and development of an automated IT/Client platform. The main task was to design and develop a web based administration interface.

**Tools & Technologies**: System development, design, MS-SQL, ASP.NET 3.5, C#, AJAX, Visual Studio 2008, Team Foundation Server.